<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</title>
    <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/home-security-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/home-security-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Best Home Security Camera Placement Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/home-security-camera-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/home-security-camera-tips/</guid>
      <description>With a property crime happening about every 3.5 seconds, home security and video surveillance top the list of homeowner needs. At a cursory glance, video surveillance seems pretty straight-forward; you just place a camera where you want to see what is happening and done. Unfortunately, it isn’t that easy. Video surveillance camera placement also involves a lot of technical knowledge to avoid all of the common problems that plague improperly installed surveillance systems, such as fuzzy images, glare, and reduced coverage area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Reason to Add Security Cameras to Your Business or Upgrade Your System Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</guid>
      <description>If the quality of the video is poor in your Video Surveillance system or it’s more than 4 or 5 years old there are several reasons why you should consider upgrading now.
Advancements in technology have made it possible to buy much better quality cameras at a much lower price. Better software has made it possible to remotely manage your system with the same functions you’d use if you were sitting in front of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Need a Professional Company to Monitor Your Security Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</guid>
      <description>Some business owners are reluctant to hire a professional monitoring company after installing a new security system. While foregoing these services might save you some cash in the short term, in the long run it can make your system far less effective. In order to get the most security benefits out of your investment, you should pair the services of professionals with your existing system. Here are a few of the top reasons why you should consider hiring the pros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Cameras Does My Home Need?</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-many-cameras-does-my-home-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-many-cameras-does-my-home-need/</guid>
      <description>When setting up a home security system, one common question many people ask themselves is “how many security cameras does my home really need?” While there’s no “one-size-fits-all” answer to that question, there are some general rules you can follow to figure out the number of cameras your home requires.
Maximize the space your cameras cover Your goal is to maximize the amount of space monitored while minimizing the number of cameras required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Safe Gun Storage (and How to Do It)</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-safe-gun-storage-and-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-safe-gun-storage-and-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest parts of being a responsible gun owner is implementing safe storage practices. The vast majority of at-home gun accidents take place when a gun has not been properly secured. It doesn’t take fancy gadgets or expensive accessories to keep your family safe– all you need is a bit of common sense, and plenty of communication.
Put the firearm away when you aren’t using it When you aren’t using it, your gun should always be kept in a locked safe or case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Sets of Numbers Not to Use for Your Pin</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</guid>
      <description>Many security systems require you to set up a four-digit pin number as your access code. Some systems will generate a pin for you, but most will ask you to pick a number of your own. Picking a good pin number can be more difficult than you might think. On one hand, you want to pick something that you and your family or coworkers can easily remember. But on the other, if it’s a simple or obvious number to you, then it will be easier for someone else to guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Simple Trick for Storing a Secure Online Password</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</guid>
      <description>Are you having a hard time remembering your online passwords? It seems like you need a password for everything, from online banking to leaving a review of your last restaurant meal. If you are planning on purchasing a password book to help you remember — stop! This is not the way to a safer and more secure computer, according to experts.
It is understandable why you would want to get a password book, after all, remembering dozens of passwords is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security for your Storage Building</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</guid>
      <description>From furniture sets to large family heirlooms, your storage building holds those items that you just aren’t quite ready to give up. Since they aren’t in your house, you may not think about these items when you’re thinking about your home security; however, for that same exact reason, the contents of your storage building are more susceptible to theft and tampering than anything inside of your home. It is important that you create a strong security system for your storage building to protect it from burglars and vandals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting your Home While on Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/protecting-your-home-while-on-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/protecting-your-home-while-on-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Vacations are times of fun and relaxation, not of stress. Unfortunately, if you’re concerned about burglary or home vandalism while you’re on the road, it can impact your entire trip and leave you rushing back to check on your home. By taking a few preventative steps before you head out, you can protect your home even while you’re away and have a wonderful, worry-free vacation.
Keep it Quiet Don’t advertise the exact dates of your vacation before you head out, and ask close family members to keep it quiet as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Tips for Apartments</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-tips-for-apartments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-tips-for-apartments/</guid>
      <description>Living in an apartment is different from living in a house, because you have lots of neighbors around you in a small space. Since it’s so different, your home security will need to be a bit different as well. You can keep your rented home safe by following these 4 tips.
Consider Your Alarm System Options Depending on your landlord or complex, your unit may already have the hardware for an alarm system installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Vandalism at your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</guid>
      <description>Whether you own a small shop or a large company, you’re probably concerned about the possibility of vandalism on your property. Vandals cause all sorts of problems, as their work devalues property, requires costly repairs, and robs you of your peace of mind. How can you keep your business safe? We’ve gathered our top three tips for preventing vandalism, so read on to find out.
Install a Security System A good security system protects both the inside and outside of your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways Your Security System Mobile App Helps Keep Your Property Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve recently been thinking about a security system upgrade, and doing your research into the new models on the market today, you have probably seen quite a few that work best when interacting with an app on your smartphone. Don’t be dismayed at yet another piece of technology and program you need to learn. These mobile apps are actually very user-friendly and make the system all the more effective. Take a look at just a few of the perks these apps bring:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Security Tips to Keep your Property Safe This Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that burglary rates actually climb this time of year? While it doesn’t snow in this part of Georgia, it does stay darker longer, giving potential burglars more hours of the night to attempt a crime. Here’s what you need to do to protect your commercial property:
#1 Lock Doors and Windows It is amazing how many business owners are careless with this basic security measure. Always lock doors and all windows, including above-ground windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Staying Safe on Your Next Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-staying-safe-on-your-next-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-staying-safe-on-your-next-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Vacations are our time to relax and unwind– so the last thing you want is to come home and find that your business has been broken into or vandalized while you were away. Fortunately, there are resources available to help you make sure that doesn’t happen. Common sense, along with the aid of a few tools, will help to keep you safe and sound. Check out these tips for keeping your property safe while you’re off exploring the world or just getting away from it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of a Relationship with a Local Security Company</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</guid>
      <description>Some of the big-name security companies want to sell you a product and then leave you to figure out the details on your own. With no dealers or customer support in your area, it can be tough to get in touch with someone who can help if you have a problem or a question about your system. That’s why we believe that it’s so important for you to have a relationship with a local security company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Home Automation Should be a Security Priority</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-home-automation-should-be-a-security-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-home-automation-should-be-a-security-priority/</guid>
      <description>When making a list of the essential security needs of your home, automation is almost never towards the top. Video is often number one or number two – it isn’t hard to grasp the necessity of video recording. And alarm is never far behind in this necessity. Both of these things are black and white and simple to understand – the same cannot be said of Home Automation. It isn’t initially clear how automation can help keep you and your family safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Checklist - Moving into Your New House</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-checklist-moving-into-your-new-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-checklist-moving-into-your-new-house/</guid>
      <description>Moving into a new home is an exciting time in anyone’s life. However, it can be quite scary as well. In order to make sure that your family and belongings are safe during the transition, you should keep a few things in mind. Follow this checklist to ensure the security of your new home.
Befriend the Neighbors Unless you’re living on a very large plot of land in the country, chances are you’ll have at least one neighbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking Safety Tips for Your Home</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/cooking-safety-tips-for-your-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/cooking-safety-tips-for-your-home/</guid>
      <description>Many home accidents occur in the kitchen. It’s understandable, with all of the sharp utensils and hot stovetops. Fires are also a more rare, but not unheard of, occurrence. However, there are several easy steps that you can take to make sure that your kitchen stays injury-free:
Don’t leave dangerous foods unattended Oil and grease are notorious for causing fires in the blink of an eye. If you’re frying food, whether it’s in a deep fryer or in a pot on the stove, you should always supervise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrical Safety for Your Home</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/electrical-safety-for-your-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/electrical-safety-for-your-home/</guid>
      <description>Most home fires are started by an electrical cord or an appliance. Frayed cords, poorly placed objects, and overworked outlets all create a hazard. Fortunately, it’s very easy to prevent these types of fires.
Keep fabrics away from lamps Lamps generate a lot of heat. This is especially true if you’re still using incandescent bulbs instead of fluorescent or LED. Curtains, blankets, and other fabrics can easily catch fire if they’re exposed to a lamp that’s been lit for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Home Fire Drills</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-home-fire-drills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-home-fire-drills/</guid>
      <description>Many homeowners don’t have a specific plan for what they’d do in the event of a fire. A failure to prepare for emergencies can cause disasters if tragedy strikes, so it’s important to know what to do in advance. This is especially true for families with small children, who might not have any idea what to do without a plan in place. Fire safety is extremely important, and it should be practiced until it becomes second nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 things your Security System can do Other Than to Just Deter Burglars</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-things-your-security-system-can-do-other-than-to-just-deter-burglars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-things-your-security-system-can-do-other-than-to-just-deter-burglars/</guid>
      <description>Technology is making leaps and bounds in the alarm system industry. Everyone knows a top-of-the-line security system can stop home break-ins but that is only the beginning. It can also prevent house fires, record what goes on during the day when you aren’t home, help monitor children or animals, and save you money! That’s just the beginning. If your alarm system is only monitoring for a thief, you’re missing out on all of this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Important Features to Look For in a Security System for your Home or Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</guid>
      <description>A security system, whether it be commercial or for personal use, is an incredibly important investment opportunity. And investing in a security system that doesn’t meet your needs wastes both your investment and your time. By focusing on these four essential features, you can rest easy knowing your home or business is protected, and that your investment is valuable and beneficial to the safe operation of either or.
Ease of Operation – You, your family, or your employees should not be forced to interact with an obscure interface when using your security system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Home for the Spring</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/secure-your-home-for-the-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/secure-your-home-for-the-spring/</guid>
      <description>Now that the holidays are over, many people feel like the most dangerous time of the year for home break-ins is over, and they can rest easy again. While it certainly is true that your home could become a prime target during the holidays, criminal activity – unfortunately – can happen at any other time of year as well. That is why it’s so important to stay on top of your home security, no matter what month it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Lockdown - What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/emergency-lockdown-what-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/emergency-lockdown-what-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>An emergency lockdown occurs when a business, a school, or other public place is facing an imminent security threat and needs to be put on high alert. Business owners may someday find themselves faced with the need to have a lockdown on their property. While it can be frightening to have to do this, it is for the safety of everyone involved, so it’s extremely important to be prepared and have a plan of action in place well before you should ever need it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>