<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</title>
    <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/business-security-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/business-security-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WHICH IS A BETTER CHOICE FOR YOUR BUSINESS: HD VIDEO SURVEILLANCE OR IP?</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/which-is-better-hd-or-ip-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/which-is-better-hd-or-ip-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 5 years Video Surveillance and Security Camera technology has changed drastically. Resolution, functionality, remote access, and analytics have gotten much better and costs of equipment and maintenance have come down. When determining the reasons for installing Security Cameras there are several considerations that should be taken into account.
 Determine the right camera for each location. Do you have existing cameras that need to be replaced? Decide if you want to view the cameras remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Reason to Add Security Cameras to Your Business or Upgrade Your System Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</guid>
      <description>If the quality of the video is poor in your Video Surveillance system or it’s more than 4 or 5 years old there are several reasons why you should consider upgrading now.
Advancements in technology have made it possible to buy much better quality cameras at a much lower price. Better software has made it possible to remotely manage your system with the same functions you’d use if you were sitting in front of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Need a Professional Company to Monitor Your Security Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</guid>
      <description>Some business owners are reluctant to hire a professional monitoring company after installing a new security system. While foregoing these services might save you some cash in the short term, in the long run it can make your system far less effective. In order to get the most security benefits out of your investment, you should pair the services of professionals with your existing system. Here are a few of the top reasons why you should consider hiring the pros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Sets of Numbers Not to Use for Your Pin</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</guid>
      <description>Many security systems require you to set up a four-digit pin number as your access code. Some systems will generate a pin for you, but most will ask you to pick a number of your own. Picking a good pin number can be more difficult than you might think. On one hand, you want to pick something that you and your family or coworkers can easily remember. But on the other, if it’s a simple or obvious number to you, then it will be easier for someone else to guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Simple Trick for Storing a Secure Online Password</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</guid>
      <description>Are you having a hard time remembering your online passwords? It seems like you need a password for everything, from online banking to leaving a review of your last restaurant meal. If you are planning on purchasing a password book to help you remember — stop! This is not the way to a safer and more secure computer, according to experts.
It is understandable why you would want to get a password book, after all, remembering dozens of passwords is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security for your Storage Building</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</guid>
      <description>From furniture sets to large family heirlooms, your storage building holds those items that you just aren’t quite ready to give up. Since they aren’t in your house, you may not think about these items when you’re thinking about your home security; however, for that same exact reason, the contents of your storage building are more susceptible to theft and tampering than anything inside of your home. It is important that you create a strong security system for your storage building to protect it from burglars and vandals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Surveillance - Why Businesses Need It</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/video-surveillance-why-businesses-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/video-surveillance-why-businesses-need-it/</guid>
      <description>Many small business owners choose to forego a video surveillance system, as they feel that the benefits they will receive from it may not justify the initial startup costs. This is unfortunate, because by installing a surveillance system on their property, business owners can provide themselves with peace of mind as well as incurring other benefits that they may not even have considered. These are our top three reasons why your business needs its own video surveillance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Vandalism at your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</guid>
      <description>Whether you own a small shop or a large company, you’re probably concerned about the possibility of vandalism on your property. Vandals cause all sorts of problems, as their work devalues property, requires costly repairs, and robs you of your peace of mind. How can you keep your business safe? We’ve gathered our top three tips for preventing vandalism, so read on to find out.
Install a Security System A good security system protects both the inside and outside of your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Points of Entry your Business Needs to Protect that may Surprise you</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-points-of-entry-your-business-needs-to-protect-that-may-surprise-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-points-of-entry-your-business-needs-to-protect-that-may-surprise-you/</guid>
      <description>Businesses owners are very aware of security threats to their inventory and physical building. Of course you don’t just let people walk through your front door at night! Chances are good that you lock up when you leave and probably even set an alarm system in case someone breaks through your lock. But is that it? Criminals who want to steal and vandalize don’t just use the easiest point of entry to accomplish their crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Determine Your Small Business’ Security Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-determine-your-small-business-security-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-determine-your-small-business-security-needs/</guid>
      <description>Your property’s integrity is not something to be taken lightly. Often, the physical presence of employees is not enough to stop a crime or catch the culprit afterwards. However, the mere existence of a security camera provides safety. An alarm system or access control system will help your small business in many ways. To decide if one is right for your company, consider the following:
Crime reduction and prevention Are you suffering though too much petty crime at your location?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Safety Tips Small Businesses Owners Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-safety-tips-small-businesses-owners-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-safety-tips-small-businesses-owners-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Owning a small business is truly a full-time job. Between supervising your staff members, keeping your clients happy, and making sure all your invoices get paid, it’s difficult to even leave the shop. And what happens once you do leave? Leaving your business overnight serves up a whole new set of problems! A study by the Ponemon Institute found that 70% of business owners express concern about the security of their companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep an Empty Property Secure</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-keep-an-empty-property-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-keep-an-empty-property-secure/</guid>
      <description>If you own a property that’s currently unoccupied, you may be concerned about how to keep it safe in your absence. This is an understandable worry, as empty buildings are more likely to be broken into than regularly-occupied ones. However, there are some easy steps you can take to keep your property safe even while it’s not being used.
Step 1: Set Up an Alarm System An alarm system is even more important for an empty property than it is for an occupied one, and that’s saying a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways Your Security System Mobile App Helps Keep Your Property Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve recently been thinking about a security system upgrade, and doing your research into the new models on the market today, you have probably seen quite a few that work best when interacting with an app on your smartphone. Don’t be dismayed at yet another piece of technology and program you need to learn. These mobile apps are actually very user-friendly and make the system all the more effective. Take a look at just a few of the perks these apps bring:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Awareness - What is it and How it Can Help Your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-awareness-what-is-it-and-how-it-can-help-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-awareness-what-is-it-and-how-it-can-help-your-business/</guid>
      <description>What is it: By definition, security awareness is the knowledge and attitude members of an organization possess regarding the protection of the physical, and especially informational, assets of that organization. Many organizations, including businesses like yours, require formal security awareness training for all staff members when they are hired, as well as periodically thereafter. This often occurs annually.
Topics covered in security awareness training often include:
  The nature of sensitive material and physical assets they may come in contact with, such as company secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Need More Than a Lock and Key to Keep Your Business Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/you-need-more-than-a-lock-and-key-to-keep-your-business-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/you-need-more-than-a-lock-and-key-to-keep-your-business-safe/</guid>
      <description>When you want to keep something safe, what do you do?
Did you say “lock it up”? While that’s a pretty good answer, a traditional lock and key are not the only products a commercial business can or even should use. There are many downsides of this type of security, and limitations on how it can be used.
Multiple Doors Requires Multiple Keys Every door requires it’s own key. One for the main door, back door, loading dock, your office, filing cabinets, supply closets, product rooms, not to mention what you need for your home and car…it starts to add up quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Security Tips to Keep your Property Safe This Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that burglary rates actually climb this time of year? While it doesn’t snow in this part of Georgia, it does stay darker longer, giving potential burglars more hours of the night to attempt a crime. Here’s what you need to do to protect your commercial property:
#1 Lock Doors and Windows It is amazing how many business owners are careless with this basic security measure. Always lock doors and all windows, including above-ground windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Beyond Cyber Security - What Physical Safety Features You Need in Place</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/thinking-beyond-cyber-security-what-physical-safety-features-you-need-in-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/thinking-beyond-cyber-security-what-physical-safety-features-you-need-in-place/</guid>
      <description>As a business owner, you probably hear a lot about cyber security. Your computers, network, servers, and mobile devices used everyday are liable to be hacked into, potentially costing you thousands. However, don’t get so wrapped up in cyber security that you forget about the actual physical building. It takes a sophisticated thief to get into your passwords and bank accounts, but anyone with a large rock can break in through a window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of a Relationship with a Local Security Company</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</guid>
      <description>Some of the big-name security companies want to sell you a product and then leave you to figure out the details on your own. With no dealers or customer support in your area, it can be tough to get in touch with someone who can help if you have a problem or a question about your system. That’s why we believe that it’s so important for you to have a relationship with a local security company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Security Guidelines for Your Employees</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/creating-security-guidelines-for-your-employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/creating-security-guidelines-for-your-employees/</guid>
      <description>As an employer, you have an obligation to do your part in keeping your employees safe while they’re on the job. You can do that by being proactive and taking steps towards safety before dangerous situations even arise. You can also make sure that everyone on the job is prepared in case a situation does come up. Having security guidelines in place is beneficial for everyone. Here are three ways you can make sure that everyone who works for you is safe:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing an Office - 3 Tips for Keeping Your Workspace Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/securing-an-office-3-tips-for-keeping-your-workspace-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/securing-an-office-3-tips-for-keeping-your-workspace-safe/</guid>
      <description>How safe is your office? If you’re like most small business owners or office managers, you may not give it much thought. Your day-to-day tasks can be so time consuming that it’s difficult to remember how many sets of keys you have handed out to past employees or what your wi-fi password is. This is a mistake! Don’t take the physical or online safety of your office lightly. Take a few minutes to consider the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 things your Security System can do Other Than to Just Deter Burglars</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-things-your-security-system-can-do-other-than-to-just-deter-burglars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-things-your-security-system-can-do-other-than-to-just-deter-burglars/</guid>
      <description>Technology is making leaps and bounds in the alarm system industry. Everyone knows a top-of-the-line security system can stop home break-ins but that is only the beginning. It can also prevent house fires, record what goes on during the day when you aren’t home, help monitor children or animals, and save you money! That’s just the beginning. If your alarm system is only monitoring for a thief, you’re missing out on all of this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Aspects of your Business - 4 Things to do in 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/automating-aspects-of-your-business-4-things-to-do-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/automating-aspects-of-your-business-4-things-to-do-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>With the new year comes the perfect time to evaluate your business’s processes and aim to streamline them. Whatever your industry, there’s a good chance there is burgeoning technology that can help you do things faster, simpler, or with less effort. As the business owner, your time is valuable. Spending less time doing the non-essential tasks frees you up to do what matters, making your customers happy and making even more profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Important Features to Look For in a Security System for your Home or Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</guid>
      <description>A security system, whether it be commercial or for personal use, is an incredibly important investment opportunity. And investing in a security system that doesn’t meet your needs wastes both your investment and your time. By focusing on these four essential features, you can rest easy knowing your home or business is protected, and that your investment is valuable and beneficial to the safe operation of either or.
Ease of Operation – You, your family, or your employees should not be forced to interact with an obscure interface when using your security system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Your Business Safe After Hours</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/keeping-your-business-safe-after-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/keeping-your-business-safe-after-hours/</guid>
      <description>Even the most diligent workers have to go home sometime, and none of us can be in two places at once. Your business is far more likely to be broken into when you’re not around versus when you’re on site. When you lock up and go home for the day, how can you be sure that your property is secure?There are a few steps you can take to ensure just that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>