<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</title>
    <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/general-security-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Security Tips on Femac Security Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/categories/general-security-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Reason to Add Security Cameras to Your Business or Upgrade Your System Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/best-reason-add-security-cameras/</guid>
      <description>If the quality of the video is poor in your Video Surveillance system or it’s more than 4 or 5 years old there are several reasons why you should consider upgrading now.
Advancements in technology have made it possible to buy much better quality cameras at a much lower price. Better software has made it possible to remotely manage your system with the same functions you’d use if you were sitting in front of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Need a Professional Company to Monitor Your Security Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/why-you-need-a-professional-company-to-monitor-your-security-systems/</guid>
      <description>Some business owners are reluctant to hire a professional monitoring company after installing a new security system. While foregoing these services might save you some cash in the short term, in the long run it can make your system far less effective. In order to get the most security benefits out of your investment, you should pair the services of professionals with your existing system. Here are a few of the top reasons why you should consider hiring the pros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Safe Gun Storage (and How to Do It)</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-safe-gun-storage-and-how-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-safe-gun-storage-and-how-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest parts of being a responsible gun owner is implementing safe storage practices. The vast majority of at-home gun accidents take place when a gun has not been properly secured. It doesn’t take fancy gadgets or expensive accessories to keep your family safe– all you need is a bit of common sense, and plenty of communication.
Put the firearm away when you aren’t using it When you aren’t using it, your gun should always be kept in a locked safe or case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Sets of Numbers Not to Use for Your Pin</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/three-sets-of-numbers-not-to-use-for-your-pin/</guid>
      <description>Many security systems require you to set up a four-digit pin number as your access code. Some systems will generate a pin for you, but most will ask you to pick a number of your own. Picking a good pin number can be more difficult than you might think. On one hand, you want to pick something that you and your family or coworkers can easily remember. But on the other, if it’s a simple or obvious number to you, then it will be easier for someone else to guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Simple Trick for Storing a Secure Online Password</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/one-simple-trick-for-storing-a-secure-online-password/</guid>
      <description>Are you having a hard time remembering your online passwords? It seems like you need a password for everything, from online banking to leaving a review of your last restaurant meal. If you are planning on purchasing a password book to help you remember — stop! This is not the way to a safer and more secure computer, according to experts.
It is understandable why you would want to get a password book, after all, remembering dozens of passwords is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security for your Storage Building</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-for-your-storage-building/</guid>
      <description>From furniture sets to large family heirlooms, your storage building holds those items that you just aren’t quite ready to give up. Since they aren’t in your house, you may not think about these items when you’re thinking about your home security; however, for that same exact reason, the contents of your storage building are more susceptible to theft and tampering than anything inside of your home. It is important that you create a strong security system for your storage building to protect it from burglars and vandals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Surveillance - Why Businesses Need It</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/video-surveillance-why-businesses-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/video-surveillance-why-businesses-need-it/</guid>
      <description>Many small business owners choose to forego a video surveillance system, as they feel that the benefits they will receive from it may not justify the initial startup costs. This is unfortunate, because by installing a surveillance system on their property, business owners can provide themselves with peace of mind as well as incurring other benefits that they may not even have considered. These are our top three reasons why your business needs its own video surveillance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting your Home While on Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/protecting-your-home-while-on-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/protecting-your-home-while-on-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Vacations are times of fun and relaxation, not of stress. Unfortunately, if you’re concerned about burglary or home vandalism while you’re on the road, it can impact your entire trip and leave you rushing back to check on your home. By taking a few preventative steps before you head out, you can protect your home even while you’re away and have a wonderful, worry-free vacation.
Keep it Quiet Don’t advertise the exact dates of your vacation before you head out, and ask close family members to keep it quiet as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Tips for Apartments</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-tips-for-apartments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-tips-for-apartments/</guid>
      <description>Living in an apartment is different from living in a house, because you have lots of neighbors around you in a small space. Since it’s so different, your home security will need to be a bit different as well. You can keep your rented home safe by following these 4 tips.
Consider Your Alarm System Options Depending on your landlord or complex, your unit may already have the hardware for an alarm system installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Vandalism at your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/preventing-vandalism-at-your-business/</guid>
      <description>Whether you own a small shop or a large company, you’re probably concerned about the possibility of vandalism on your property. Vandals cause all sorts of problems, as their work devalues property, requires costly repairs, and robs you of your peace of mind. How can you keep your business safe? We’ve gathered our top three tips for preventing vandalism, so read on to find out.
Install a Security System A good security system protects both the inside and outside of your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Points of Entry your Business Needs to Protect that may Surprise you</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-points-of-entry-your-business-needs-to-protect-that-may-surprise-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-points-of-entry-your-business-needs-to-protect-that-may-surprise-you/</guid>
      <description>Businesses owners are very aware of security threats to their inventory and physical building. Of course you don’t just let people walk through your front door at night! Chances are good that you lock up when you leave and probably even set an alarm system in case someone breaks through your lock. But is that it? Criminals who want to steal and vandalize don’t just use the easiest point of entry to accomplish their crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Determine Your Small Business’ Security Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-determine-your-small-business-security-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-determine-your-small-business-security-needs/</guid>
      <description>Your property’s integrity is not something to be taken lightly. Often, the physical presence of employees is not enough to stop a crime or catch the culprit afterwards. However, the mere existence of a security camera provides safety. An alarm system or access control system will help your small business in many ways. To decide if one is right for your company, consider the following:
Crime reduction and prevention Are you suffering though too much petty crime at your location?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Safety Tips Small Businesses Owners Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-safety-tips-small-businesses-owners-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-safety-tips-small-businesses-owners-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Owning a small business is truly a full-time job. Between supervising your staff members, keeping your clients happy, and making sure all your invoices get paid, it’s difficult to even leave the shop. And what happens once you do leave? Leaving your business overnight serves up a whole new set of problems! A study by the Ponemon Institute found that 70% of business owners express concern about the security of their companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep an Empty Property Secure</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-keep-an-empty-property-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/how-to-keep-an-empty-property-secure/</guid>
      <description>If you own a property that’s currently unoccupied, you may be concerned about how to keep it safe in your absence. This is an understandable worry, as empty buildings are more likely to be broken into than regularly-occupied ones. However, there are some easy steps you can take to keep your property safe even while it’s not being used.
Step 1: Set Up an Alarm System An alarm system is even more important for an empty property than it is for an occupied one, and that’s saying a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways Your Security System Mobile App Helps Keep Your Property Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-ways-your-security-system-mobile-app-helps-keep-your-property-safe/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve recently been thinking about a security system upgrade, and doing your research into the new models on the market today, you have probably seen quite a few that work best when interacting with an app on your smartphone. Don’t be dismayed at yet another piece of technology and program you need to learn. These mobile apps are actually very user-friendly and make the system all the more effective. Take a look at just a few of the perks these apps bring:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Awareness - What is it and How it Can Help Your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-awareness-what-is-it-and-how-it-can-help-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-awareness-what-is-it-and-how-it-can-help-your-business/</guid>
      <description>What is it: By definition, security awareness is the knowledge and attitude members of an organization possess regarding the protection of the physical, and especially informational, assets of that organization. Many organizations, including businesses like yours, require formal security awareness training for all staff members when they are hired, as well as periodically thereafter. This often occurs annually.
Topics covered in security awareness training often include:
  The nature of sensitive material and physical assets they may come in contact with, such as company secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Security Tips to Keep your Property Safe This Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-security-tips-to-keep-your-property-safe-this-winter/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that burglary rates actually climb this time of year? While it doesn’t snow in this part of Georgia, it does stay darker longer, giving potential burglars more hours of the night to attempt a crime. Here’s what you need to do to protect your commercial property:
#1 Lock Doors and Windows It is amazing how many business owners are careless with this basic security measure. Always lock doors and all windows, including above-ground windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Beyond Cyber Security - What Physical Safety Features You Need in Place</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/thinking-beyond-cyber-security-what-physical-safety-features-you-need-in-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/thinking-beyond-cyber-security-what-physical-safety-features-you-need-in-place/</guid>
      <description>As a business owner, you probably hear a lot about cyber security. Your computers, network, servers, and mobile devices used everyday are liable to be hacked into, potentially costing you thousands. However, don’t get so wrapped up in cyber security that you forget about the actual physical building. It takes a sophisticated thief to get into your passwords and bank accounts, but anyone with a large rock can break in through a window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Staying Safe on Your Next Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-staying-safe-on-your-next-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/tips-for-staying-safe-on-your-next-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Vacations are our time to relax and unwind– so the last thing you want is to come home and find that your business has been broken into or vandalized while you were away. Fortunately, there are resources available to help you make sure that doesn’t happen. Common sense, along with the aid of a few tools, will help to keep you safe and sound. Check out these tips for keeping your property safe while you’re off exploring the world or just getting away from it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of a Relationship with a Local Security Company</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/the-importance-of-a-relationship-with-a-local-security-company/</guid>
      <description>Some of the big-name security companies want to sell you a product and then leave you to figure out the details on your own. With no dealers or customer support in your area, it can be tough to get in touch with someone who can help if you have a problem or a question about your system. That’s why we believe that it’s so important for you to have a relationship with a local security company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Checklist - Moving into Your New House</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-checklist-moving-into-your-new-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/security-checklist-moving-into-your-new-house/</guid>
      <description>Moving into a new home is an exciting time in anyone’s life. However, it can be quite scary as well. In order to make sure that your family and belongings are safe during the transition, you should keep a few things in mind. Follow this checklist to ensure the security of your new home.
Befriend the Neighbors Unless you’re living on a very large plot of land in the country, chances are you’ll have at least one neighbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Signs it’s Time for a Security System Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/6-signs-its-time-for-a-security-system-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/6-signs-its-time-for-a-security-system-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>You buy a new phone every few years when great new features are released, you make sure your television gets better and clearer, you even opt for the higher trim package in your car so you utilize the best technology while you drive. So why are you using an out-of-date security system to keep your business safe? Just like the other tech in your life, the capabilities and features of your commercial alarm system or video surveillance have been changing too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Important Features to Look For in a Security System for your Home or Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/4-important-features-to-look-for-in-a-security-system-for-your-home-or-business/</guid>
      <description>A security system, whether it be commercial or for personal use, is an incredibly important investment opportunity. And investing in a security system that doesn’t meet your needs wastes both your investment and your time. By focusing on these four essential features, you can rest easy knowing your home or business is protected, and that your investment is valuable and beneficial to the safe operation of either or.
Ease of Operation – You, your family, or your employees should not be forced to interact with an obscure interface when using your security system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Lockdown - What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/emergency-lockdown-what-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/emergency-lockdown-what-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>An emergency lockdown occurs when a business, a school, or other public place is facing an imminent security threat and needs to be put on high alert. Business owners may someday find themselves faced with the need to have a lockdown on their property. While it can be frightening to have to do this, it is for the safety of everyone involved, so it’s extremely important to be prepared and have a plan of action in place well before you should ever need it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-Wave - What it is and what you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/z-wave-what-it-is-and-what-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/z-wave-what-it-is-and-what-you-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard the phrase “Z- Wave” lately in passing from those in the home and business security industry. If you’re just beginning to learn about home and business automation and how everything can blend together, then Z-Wave is something you should learn more about.
What is Z-Wave? Z-Wave is a wireless communication standard used in a majority of the leading automation devices on today’s market. Similar to wi-fi and other wireless communication, this technology allows devices to “talk” to each other and carry out specific functions like adjusting thermostats, turning lights on and off, or locking and unlocking doors, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of HD Surveillance Cameras for Your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/benefits-of-hd-surveillance-cameras-for-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/benefits-of-hd-surveillance-cameras-for-your-business/</guid>
      <description>Surveillance cameras are an essential security investment for your business, and when the value of that investment is defined by the clarity of the recording, HD capability matters. If you’ve been shopping around for specifics, you’ve probably found two different types of security cameras: standard definition and high definition (HD). Standard definition is cheaper, and you might be thinking “I’m getting a camera either way, so why pay more?” Well, it turns out, investing in HD can both add value to your investment and help better identify threats to your business’s security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to Replace Your Security System</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/when-to-replace-your-security-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/when-to-replace-your-security-system/</guid>
      <description>You don’t have the options you need. Many years ago, alarm systems were pretty standard, and there wasn’t a lot of variation from one to another. Those days are long gone. Today, alarm systems sport more features than the ones rolled out years ago. Now you can monitor your property when you aren’t on site with smartphone apps that live-stream directly from your on-site cameras. You can also have your system automate the lights inside your business before you arrive, which is really helpful for when you’re coming in for an early morning, or when you want to make it seem as if someone is on site when they really aren’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Expert Tips for Keeping Valuables Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-expert-tips-for-keeping-valuables-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.femacsecuritysolutions.com/3-expert-tips-for-keeping-valuables-safe/</guid>
      <description>Whether it’s your home or office, chances are you keep a lot of valuable items and information close at hand. ID documents, bank statements, and fine jewelry are just a few of the things that need to be protected from falling into the wrong hands. You can prevent theft by taking a few simple steps to protect the things that matter most to you.
#1 Utilize a Proper Safe A good safe should be fire-retardant, break-in resistant, and bolted to the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>